Some secrets take us to the edge.
Edge of Darkness is a crime, drama, mystery film directed by Martin Campbell.
As a seasoned homicide detective, Thomas Craven has
seen the bleakest side of humanity.
But nothing prepares him for the toughest investigation of his
life: the search for his only daughter Emma's killer.
Now, he is on a personal mission to uncover the disturbing secrets surrounding her murder,
including corporate corruption, government collusion and Emma's own mysterious life.
Craven, played by Mel Gibson.
Jedburgh, played by Ray Winstone.
Jack Bennett, played by Danny Huston.
Emma Craven, played by Bojana Novaković.
Burnham, played by Shawn Roberts.
Millroy, played by David Aaron Baker.
Edge of Darkness is a 2010 conspiracy crime thriller film directed by Martin Campbell, written
by William Monahan and Andrew Bovell, and starring Mel Gibson and Ray Winstone.
A British-American co-production, it is based on the 1985 BBC television
series of the same name, which was likewise directed by Campbell.
This was Gibson's first screen lead since Signs (2002), and follows a detective investigating the murder of
his activist daughter, while uncovering political conspiracies and cover-ups in the process.
It was released on 29 January 2010.
It received mixed reviews from critics, though Gibson's and Winstone's performances were praised, and
grossed $81 million against its $80 million production budget which made it a box-office bomb.
The film explores themes of assassination, senator,
conspiracy theory, cover-up, murder.
The tone is intense and mind_bending and dark.